Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是的，是的，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是的，是的，队长！
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性、黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
♪ 如果是航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后掉到甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好了吗？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
Oh, Lady Upturn!
哦，翻转女士！
Always a delight to
have you back at our gallery.
总是令人高兴
您回到我们的画廊了吗？
I'm bored by the art
in my home.
我对艺术感到厌倦
在我家。
What do you have that's
new and interesting?
你有什么那是
新奇有趣？
Ick.
恶心。
Oh, I-I've been saving
our newest and finest
哦，我-我一直在节省
我们最新最好的
pieces just for you.
专为您打造的作品。
This work is by one of
our emerging artists.
这项工作是由其中一位
我们的新兴艺术家。
Bleh.
布莱赫。
Where did they emerge
from, under a rock?
他们在哪里出现
从岩石下？
Ah, how did you know?
啊，你怎么知道？
Lady Upturn,
I am so, so sorry.
女士逆袭，
我实在是太、太抱歉了。
I should never have
shown you that dreck.
我不应该有
给你看了那个烂摊子。
Never fear.
永远不要害怕。
This next work is
guaranteed to excite.
下一个作品是
保证令人兴奋。
Bikini Bottom's
premier dance troupe
比基尼泳裤
首屈一指的舞蹈团
has created
a performance so new,
已创建
如此新颖的表演，
even they don't
know what it is yet.
即使他们不
还知道它是什么。
Yawn.
打哈欠。
Moving in time to
music is hardly new.
及时移动到
音乐并不新鲜。
This does nothing
for me, either.
这没有任何作用
对我来说也是如此。
Oh, surely, there's
something here you'll enjoy.
哦，当然有
这里有你会喜欢的东西。
No, I'm afraid not.
不，恐怕不是。
Regigilled!
重新调整！
I need a walk to clear my mind.
我需要散散步来理清思绪。
Carry me.
- Very good, ma'am.
带我吧
- 很好，女士。
Alas, I have failed.
唉，我失败了。
Ow.
噢。
Whoo!
呼！
No!
不！
- Oh?
- Oh.
- 哦？
- 哦。
My apologies, madam.
抱歉，女士。
I shall remove your person
from this cacophony at once.
我要把你的人除掉
立即从这刺耳的声音中消失。
No, no, Regigilled.
Take me closer.
不，不，雷吉利德。
带我靠近一点。
As you wish.
如你所愿。
You, there!
你在那里！
Yes, you!
是的，就是你！
I'm allowed to play
my clarinet here.
我被允许玩
我的单簧管在这里。
It's a free ocean, you know.
你知道，这是一片自由的海洋。
I'm not stopping!
我不会停下来！
Stop?
停止？
I wouldn't dream of it.
我做梦都不会想到这一点。
That is the most interesting
and avant-garde music
这才是最有趣的
和前卫音乐
I have heard in years.
我听了很多年了。
Oh, it is sublime.
哦，真是崇高。
Do you have a patron?
I simply must be yours.
你有赞助人吗？
我只是必须属于你。
Yeah, yeah, very funny.
是啊是啊，非常搞笑。
What is this, one of those
hidden-camera TV prank shows?
这是什么，其中之一
隐藏摄像头电视恶作剧？
Heavens, no.
天啊，不。
Television
is the lowest form of art.
电视
是最低级的艺术形式。
Regigilled, pay the man.
重新登记，付钱给那个人。
You can't just buy the soul
of a raw talent like myself.
你不能只买灵魂
像我这样的原始人才。
Lady, you just bought
yourself an artist.
小姐，你刚买的
你自己是一位艺术家。
Hello, losers.
你好，失败者。
Hi, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
What's with all the joy,
Mr. Squidward?
满心欢喜又有何妨
章鱼哥先生？
I'm a paid musician now.
我现在是一名付费音乐家。
You?
Musician? Paid?
你？
音乐家？有薪酬的？
Laugh all you want,
but it's true.
想笑就笑吧
但这是真的。
I don't need this minimum-wage
prison anymore.
我不需要这个最低工资
不再坐牢了。
I quit.
我不干了。
Huh?
啊？
Wow!
哇！
Squidward's dreams are
finally coming true.
章鱼哥的梦想是
终于实现了。
Welcome to your new home,
Mr. Tentacles.
欢迎来到你的新家，
触手先生。
Oh, my, it's incredible.
哦，天哪，这太不可思议了。
But where are you
going to live?
但你在哪里
要去住吗？
The mansion is mine.
豪宅是我的。
You just get one tiny room.
你只得到一间小房间。
Oh, my.
哦，我的。
Wow!
哇！
I cannot wait to show you off
我迫不及待地想向你炫耀
to my wealthy,
taste-making friends,
致我的富人，
品味交友，
so you better get writing.
所以你最好开始写作。
Yes, ma'am, ma'am.
是的，女士，女士。
Toodle-oo, you genius, you.
Toodle-oo，你是天才。
Out of my way, peon.
别挡我的路，苦工。
So sorry, my lord.
非常抱歉，陛下。
Wow, Squidward.
哇，章鱼哥。
That was very, uh,
confident of you.
那是非常，呃，
对你有信心。
Yes.
是的。
Being an artist requires
having an artist's temperament,
成为一名艺术家需要
具有艺术家气质，
you boob.
你个布布。
What took you so long?
是什么让你花了这么长时间？
Now, then, I'm only
here to invite you
那么现在我只
在此邀请您
both to my big debut concert.
都参加了我的大型首场音乐会。
Huh?
啊？
Witness my rebirth
on the grandest stage
见证我的重生
在最盛大的舞台上
in Bikini Bottom...
在比基尼底部...
if you can get the time off.
如果你能抽出时间的话。
Somehow,
he's even more annoying now
不知何故，
他现在更烦人了
than when he worked here.
比他在这里工作时还要多。
Wait, Mr. Krabs.
等等，蟹老板。
Squidward is just being
insufferable because his dreams
章鱼哥只是
因为他的梦想而难以忍受
are coming true.
即将实现。
We have to go and support him.
We're his friends.
我们必须去支持他。
我们是他的朋友。
Well, "friends"
is a strong word, but fine.
嗯，“朋友”
这是一个很强烈的词，但是很好。
Hiya, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
Mr. Krabs and I just wanted
to wish you luck
蟹老板和我只是想要
祝你好运
before your big show.
在你的大型演出之前。
Luck?
Don't be stupid.
运气？
别傻了。
I'm the greatest musician
who ever lived.
我是最伟大的音乐家
谁曾住过。
Rich people say so.
有钱人都这么说。
- Can't argue with money.
- Now, go find your seats.
- 不能与金钱争论。
- 现在，去找座位吧。
I'm in the middle
of my pre-show ritual,
我在中间
我的演出前仪式，
and I don't want
to be bothered.
我不想
被打扰。
Eh.
呃。
Good evening, music lovers.
晚上好，音乐爱好者们。
Like me, I'm sure you are tired
of the same old notes being
和我一样，我相信你也累了
相同的旧笔记是
played the same old ways.
还是用同样的老方法。
Well, fear not.
好吧，不用害怕。
Tonight you will finally
hear something new.
今晚你终于
听到一些新的东西。
Tonight I present to you
今晚我向你呈现
Mr. Squidward Tentacles.
章鱼哥触手先生。
Forget your wedding.
忘记你的婚礼。
Forget the birth
of your first child.
忘记出生
你的第一个孩子的。
This is going to be
这将是
the greatest night
of your lives.
最伟大的夜晚
你的生活。
all:
Oh!
全部：
哦！
Oh, isn't it
dazzling, Doctor?
哦，不是吗
眼花缭乱，博士？
Oh.
哦。
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
唔。
嗯嗯。
Mm-hmm.
Yes.
嗯嗯。
是的。
Pardon me, Lady Upturn.
请原谅，Upturn 女士。
May I...?
我可以...？
Of course, Dr. Fishberg.
当然，菲什伯格博士。
Lady Upturn, there's
a jellyfish blocking your ears.
翻转女士，有
水母挡住了你的耳朵。
Oh, goodness!
哦，天哪！
It must have gotten
stuck up there during my walk
一定已经得到了
我走路时被卡在那里
through Jellyfish Fields.
穿过水母田。
Oh. Is that what
he really sounds like?
哦。是这样吗
他听起来真的像吗？
This music is terrible!
这音乐太可怕了！
Indeed.
的确。
The jellyfish's buzzing
must have altered the noise
水母在嗡嗡叫
一定改变了噪音
to be more pleasurable for you.
为您带来更多乐趣。
Oh!
哦！
Stop that racket!
停止那个喧闹！
Stop it!
停下来！
How dare you interrupt m--
你怎么敢打断我——
I have a confession to make.
我有件事要坦白。
A jellyfish was
obstructing my ears,
一只水母是
挡住我的耳朵，
so I hadn't truly heard
this fraud's music.
所以我并没有真正听到
这个骗局的音乐。
And now that I have,
现在我有了，
I am offended!
我很生气！
Hey!
嘿！
To make up for this
abysmal performance,
为了弥补这一点
糟糕的表现，
I would like to invite
you all back to my home
我想邀请
你们都回我家吧
to experience real music
体验真正的音乐
by my newest artiste,
Maestro Patrick Star.
由我最新的艺人创作，
帕特里克·斯塔大师。
What?
什么？
Yay!
耶！
Huh? Uh...
啊？呃...
Oh.
哦。
- Whoo! Go, Squidward!
- Encore! Encore!
- 呼！走吧，章鱼哥！
- 安可！安可！
We want more!
我们想要更多！
- We want more!
- Do you really mean it?
- 我们想要更多！
- 你真的是这个意思吗？
Of course.
当然。
We've got jellyfish.
我们有水母。
Huh.
呵呵。
I'll take what I can get.
我会拿走我能得到的。
- Yeah! Whoo!
- Whoo-hoo!
- 是的！呼！
- 呼呼！
Come on, Squidward!
加油，章鱼哥！